W. Randle Iredale fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
W. Randle Iredale fonds
1964 - 1978
F-47
Q100152742
2 cm of textual records 35 photographs 77 negatives 4 contact sheets 128 slides 8 bound volumes of architectural drawings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 35 photographs located in F-47-0-0-2
Iredale, W. Randle
W. Randle Iredale is one of the contributors to the architecture of Simon Fraser University. He and his partner, William R. Rhone, were responsible for designing and building the Science Complex according to design specifications outlined by Erickson and Massey (the architects responsible for the overall design of the university). Rhone and Iredale built the Science Complex in three phases based on preliminary drawings by Erickson and Massey, but added their own ideas and innovations to the building.
Iredale was born in Calgary, Alberta in 1929. In 1955 he received a degree in architecture from the University of British Columbia, and went to work for McCarter and Nairne until Iredale was registered in 1957. He had his own practice from 1957 to 1959, and then formed a partnership with William R. Rhone. In 1963 Rhone and Iredale submitted an entry to the contest to design the new university that would be built on top of Burnaby Mountain. Their design finished in second place. According to the contest parameters, the top five winners would each be given a contract to build a section of the campus according to the winner's overall design. Originally, Rhone and Iredale chose the Academic Quadrangle, but changed their minds and picked the Science Complex, which Chancellor Gordon Shrum had assured them would be expanded on a regular basis. The Science Complex was built in three phases between 1964 and 1971: Phase I was substantially completed by August 1, 1965, Phase II was completed September 7, 1966 and Phase III was completed in 1971. Rhone and Iredale also designed and built the student pub, circa 1970.
published
Full
Revised
Title the of fonds is based on its provenance.
Fonds consists of records reflecting W. Randle Iredale's contribution to the architecture of Simon Fraser University. Records reflect the three phases of designing and building the Science Complex. Includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, news releases, negatives, contact sheets, slides, 8 x 10 photographs, and architectural drawings.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist. Photographs in file F-47-0-0-2 were removed from a photograph album and numbered according to the order in which they originally appeared. Original reference numbers for slides and negatives, where they existed, have been transcribed and preserved onto the current housing.
Photographic materials; Architectural drawings; Textual records; Buildings and structures
W. Randle Iredale donated the publicity records, photographs, negatives, and slides to the SFU Archives in 1999. The architectural drawings (as bound reports) were added to the fonds in 2006 by the archivist. There is no information regarding the source or acquisition date of these drawings.
All accessions have been processed as of February 2006. No further accruals are expected.
Please consult the inventory for the Robert F. Harrison fonds, F-46 and the Zoltan Kiss fonds, F-48.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
A file list is available.
- SFU Publicity, 1964 - 1970; F-47-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Open
  Creator's original file classification code: file 6324.
- Photo Album - SFU Science Complex - Phase 1, 1965; F-47-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
  Textual records; Photographic materials
  Pending review
- Negatives - SFU Science Complex - Phase 1, 1965; F-47-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
- SFU Science Complex - Phase III Concept Presentation, 1966; F-47-0-0-0-4
- SFU Science Complex - Phase III Design Presentation, 1966; F-47-0-0-0-5
- SFU Physical Plant Building, 1978; F-47-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
- SFU photographs and reprints, F-47-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
- Slides - Central service, centre #1, Science Complex, pub, F-47-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
- SFU photographs (paper copies), F-47-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 47-1)
- SFU Science Complex - Phase III Working Drawings, 1967; F-47-0-0-0-10
- SFU Science Complex - Phase III Lecture Theatre, 1966; F-47-0-0-0-11
- SFU Centre No. 1 Pre-Design Study, 1970; F-47-0-0-0-12
- SFU Centre No. 1 Programme Report, 1970; F-47-0-0-0-13
- SFU Centre No. 1 Programme Amendment A, 1970; F-47-0-0-0-14
- Burnaby Mountain System Control Centre, BC Hydro and Power Authority, vol. 2, 1967; F-47-0-0-0-15